Contact

Shree Apartment. Flat No 303. 1, Jnanendra Avenue. 9748410639 (Mobile) ks.dreamzunlimited@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/kaushiksahoo0704 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Algorithms
Product Development
Software Development

Kaushik Sahoo

AWS| .Net Full Stack| Microservices Greater Kolkata Area

Summary

More than 10 years of hands-on experience providing IT solutions for leading Banking and Financial Enterprises.

Have hands on experience in design and developing applications using AWS cloud services like S3, Lambda, API Gateway, SQS, SNS, Cloudformation, Cloudwatch, Dynamo DB, Athena and Dot Net Core.

Worked through all the phases of SDLC. Managed development teams spread across multiple locations globally.

Business and domain knowledge include Brokerage and Advisory Business, Card and Payments, Fuel Card, Banking and Financial Services.

Have a good understanding of SOLID and object-oriented concepts with application architecture, design patterns and Micro services. Have experience in design and develop using various technologies like C#, .Net Core, MVC, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, ASP.Net and Unit Tests using NUnit and MOQ frameworks. Worked with SOAP and REST based services using WCF and Web API. Experience in building Single Page Applications (SPA) with Angular.

Worked extensively in SAFe Agile using Scrum and methodologies.

Experience

Cognizant

13 years

Technical Manager March 2021 - Present (4 years 3 months) West Bengal, India

Senior Associate - Application Architect, Banking And Financial Services

June 2012 - Present (13 years)

Kolkata Area, India

Design, Development and Maintenance of various Banking and Financial products.

Tata Elxsi Senior Engineer, Wireless Business Unit March 2009 - June 2012 (3 years 4 months) Bangalore

Design and Development of Wireless Protocol Stacks based on IEEE 802.16e WiMAX and 3GPP Long Term Evolution Protocol.

Experienced in development in the Base Station (WiMAX and LTE), Mobile Station (WiMAX) and Access Service Network side (WiMAX). Have been part of development of features like Network Entry, Mobility, Idle Mode, Sleep Mode etc.

Education

Narula Institute of Technology
B-Tech, Computer Science and Engineering · (2004 - 2008)